skout.com 2014-02-19

# Skout :: Privacy

Last updated: February 4th, 2014

This Privacy Policy (the "Policy") explains how information is collected, used and disclosed by Skout, Inc. with respect to your access and use of Skout, Inc.'s services, whether through our websites (located at www.skout.com, www.flurv.skout.com or www.boyahoy.skout.com), Skout, Inc.'s mobile applications (Skout, Flurv and BoyAhoy) or in connection with social networking services (together referred to below as "Skout" or the "Service").

## What Information Do We Collect?

We collect certain information when you connect to or use Skout in various ways. This information may be information that can identify you as a person or non-personal information and is either collected automatically or as a result of your specific input of the information. All information collected in any way is referred to collectively in this Policy as "Information." All Information is currently processed and stored in the United States on either Skout’s servers or within Amazon Web Services.

### Website Visit

We automatically collect information when you visit our websites. We collect your IP address and browser header (version and type of browser) in a log file. We also collect your Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks.

We may also automatically collect certain Information through the use of "cookies" or web beacons. These are small files that your browser places on your computer. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with the websites, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our websites, and to improve our Service.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit.

We may feature advertisements served by third party advertising companies which deliver cookies to your computer so the advertisements you see can be tracked. These advertisers may use information about your visits to our websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Third party advertising companies may collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons or "gifs", are electronic images that may be used on our websites. Advertisers may use web beacons in connection with our websites in order to collect and use data regarding advertisement performance and your interests for the purpose of delivering relevant advertising to you.

You may click on the following links: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ and http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ for information on how to opt-out of the use of cookies or Web beacons.

### Sign Up/Install

You may be required to provide the following Information to Skout when you install a Skout mobile application or sign up for the Services: your email address, your username, your gender, your age, your interests and your picture (for your profile or for the "Backstage" feature). We automatically collect the time you connect ("timestamp"). Also, if you sign up via an ad click, we automatically collect your device type and unique device identifier

### Login

We collect the following Information each time you log in to Skout: your geographic location (specified by latitude and longitude), your IP address and the MAC address of the device you are using. If you are logging in on the iOS platform, we also collect the Identifier for Vendor ("IFV"), the Identifier for Advertiser ("IFA"), your UDID (in versions prior to 3.6.0) or Open UDID. If you are logging in on an Android platform, we also collect your Android ID, your input method editor ("IME") and your mobile equipment identifier ("MEID"). Also, if you log in through an ad identifier, we collect your device type and a timestamp. We collect all of the above Information automatically as part of the log in process.

### Sign up via Facebook

We collect the following Information when you sign up for Skout via your Facebook account: your name, your email address, your Facebook profile picture, your gender, your birthday, how many Facebook friends you have, your Facebook ID and a timestamp. We collect all of the above information automatically as part of the Facebook sign up process. If you want us to delete the data we receive from Facebook about you, please contact us at support@skout.com.

### Sign up via Google+

We collect the following Information when you sign up for Skout via your Google account: your name, your email address, your Google profile picture, your gender, your birthday, your Google ID and a timestamp. We collect all of the above information automatically as part of the Google+ sign up process. If you want us to delete the data we receive from Google about you, please contact us at support@skout.com.

### Social Media

As indicated above, we may provide you with the option to connect your Skout account to your account on a social networking site for the purpose of logging in, uploading information or enabling certain features on the Service. By connecting your Skout account to your account on any social networking site, you consent to the continuous release of information about you from the social networking site to Skout while the accounts remain connected. 

### Add Friends

We collect the following Information when you add friends, either via your Facebook account or your address book: If you choose to add a friend through your device’s address book, we collect your friend’s name, phone number and/or email address. If you choose to add friends through Facebook, we access your friend’s Facebook name and Facebook ID. When inviting friends from your address book or your Facebook account, you must manually choose each person that you want to invite; we do not "auto-invite" your entire address book or set of Facebook friends. We collect all of the above information automatically as part of the process of adding friends.

### Chat

We collect the following information when you use Skout’s chat feature: the text of your chat session, any pictures you’ve shared in the chat session and a timestamp.

### Location Information

In addition to the geographic Information collected when you log in, we automatically receive an approximation of your geographic location when you use the Service. When you use the Skout App on a mobile device, you can allow Skout to receive your more precise location by enabling or disabling location services through your mobile device settings. 

### Platforms

In the course of providing our Service on third party platforms, such as Apple’s App Store, the platforms may collect Information about you or receive Information from us in order for the platform to provide or analyze their services. Please note that these platforms were developed and administered by people or companies not affiliated with or controlled by Skout and that Skout is not responsible for the actions of those people or companies. You should carefully review the terms of service and privacy policies of the platforms that you use to access our Service.

## How Do We Use the Information We Collect?

We use Information for the following purposes:

  * to administer our websites and provide our services or information you request
  * to process and complete any transactions;
  * to promote Skout in general;
  * to provide you with advertising of interest to you;
  * to identify your location to other Skout users, if you choose to enable this feature;
  * to respond to your emails, submissions, questions, comments, requests, and complaints and provide customer service;
  * to provide you with additional points and rewards from watching video advertisements, and to increase the functionality and user friendliness of our services;
  * to monitor and analyze user behavior and trends;
  * to track visitor movement and activity in the aggregate (for example, to give us information about what parts of the websites users are visiting)
  * to personalize and improve Skout products and features and your experiences when you use Skout, such as providing content or features that match your profile, location or interests;
  * to send you confirmations, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages and otherwise facilitate your use of, and our administration and operation of, our services;
  * help prevent fraud or other misuse
  * to connect with your friends (when instructed by you); and
  * for any other stated purpose for which the Information was collected.

In addition, we may use your email address to send you emails for both transactional (e.g., confirmation of or issues with Services) and promotional purposes (e.g., newsletters, new product offerings, special discounts, event notifications and third-party offers). Email messages we send to you may contain code that enables our database to track your usage of the emails, including whether the email was opened and what links (if any) were clicked. If you would rather not receive promotional emails from us, please see the section in each email labeled "Choice/Opt-Out".

## With Whom Do We Share Your Information?

We may share Information as follows:

  * with in-app advertisers or advertising networks for the purpose of providing advertising of interest to you within Skout or advertising Skout in other locations;
  * with analytics providers for the purpose of analyzing user data;
  * with service providers who are working with us in connection with the operation of our site or our services;
  * anonymous or aggregate data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other similar purposes;
  * when you give us your consent to do so;
  * when we believe in good faith that we are lawfully authorized or required to do so or that doing so is reasonably necessary or appropriate to comply with the law or legal processes or respond to lawful requests or legal authorities, including responding to lawful subpoenas, warrants or court orders;
  * to enforce or apply our privacy policy, our terms of use or our other policies or agreements;
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of Skout, our users, or others; and
  * in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition, or in any other situation where personal information may be disclosed or transferred as one of our business assets.

## What Information Can the Other Users See?

A main purpose of using Skout is to meet and interact with new people. The information you enter in your profile, including your backstage pics, your location (if you enable that feature), photos you upload to your profile, and virtual gifts you receive, are visible to all Skout users within your age category. Other Skout users may also see the fact that you have viewed their Skout profiles. 

Any text and images you send to a chat recipient will be visible to that recipient. Skout also has "backstage pics," which are pictures posted by a user on his or her profile. Backstage pics can be seen by another user if he or she pays with Skout points to "unlock" another user’s backstage pics. The "unlock" is valid for 24 hours. There is no explicit acceptance by a user posting backstage pics required in order to let another user view the backstage pics. We review all public pictures. If the picture is rejected, that picture or link will not be published.

## How Do We Use Your Information for Advertising and Analytics?

We may allow advertisers and analytics providers to collect your Information within the Service and they may share it with us. Advertisers may collect your Information through the use of tracking technologies such as browser cookies and web beacons. The Information collected may be used to offer advertisements of particular interest to you and to analyze your activity within the Service to improve your experience. 

When we purchase advertising space on the mobile platform, we share a list of UDIDs and other device ID Information with the ad networks with which we are interacting. Ad networks use this information to match the list of identifiers with identifiers they can confirm have downloaded or installed our Service through an advertisement. When we sell advertising space on the mobile platform, ad networks may collect the following user Information in order to provide advertising of interest to you: IP address, http: header information, location (including longitude/latitude), age, gender and unique device IDs. We do not provide to ad networks names, user names, phone numbers, or email addresses. We also use third parties such as Flurry and MixPanel to collect and analyze your Information. You can opt-out of Flurry Analytics tracking at http://www.flurry.com/user-opt-out.html. We use Google Analytics to track your visits to our websites.

## Links to Other Sites

Skout may contain links to other sites and apps, including in advertisements. Any information you provide on those sites is provided directly to the owner of that site and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our privacy policy does not apply to such sites, and we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of those sites.

## What Steps Do We Take To Protect Your Information?

While we take measures to protect your Information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure and alteration, despite our efforts, no security measures are impenetrable, and no method of data transmission can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse.

## Accessing and Modifying Your Information

If you have an account, you can access and modify certain Information that you provided to us that is associated with your account by logging in and editing your profile information on Skout. Note that you may not modify your location Information, which is automatically collected. To request modifications to any Information that you cannot edit via the Service, please contact Skout’s user support at support@skout.com.

## Opting Out

You may "opt out" of receiving marketing or promotional emails and push notifications from us by changing your account preferences or by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt out of these messages, you will still receive emails from us, about your account, our services and other pertinent information related to our services. These communications are considered part of the service and your account, which you cannot opt-out from receiving.

## Deactivating Your Account and Deleting Account Information

You can deactivate your account by selecting the "deactivate" link. Deactivating your account lets you remove your profile without permanently deleting it. When you deactivate your account, other users will no longer see your profile or Information. We reserve the right, but are not required, to permanently delete your Information if you do not reactivate your account within 60 days of deactivation. If you would like your account Information permanently deleted, you may contact Skout customer support at support@skout.com and request permanent deletion. We will then delete all of your account Information.

## International Users

If you are located outside the United States, please note that we may transfer your Information to the United States (or any other country in which we operate) and process it there. By using Skout, you consent to the collection, transfer, use, storage and disclosure of your Information as described in this Policy.

## Our Policy Toward Children

Our service is not directed to children under 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal Information from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected personal Information of a child under 13, we will take steps to delete such Information from our files as soon as possible.

## Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents may request and obtain from Skout once a year, free of charge, a list of third parties who receive personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes and the categories of personal information disclosed to those third parties. To request this information sharing disclosure, please contact Skout at support@skout.com.

## Changes to the Policy

Any Information that is collected is subject to the Policy in effect at the time such Information is collected. We may, however, modify the Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Policy, we will notify you of such changes by posting them on Skout or by sending you an email or other notification, and we will indicate when such changes will become effective. By continuing to access or use Skout after those changes become effective, you are agreeing to have your Information collected, used and disclosed as described in the modified Policy.

## Online Safety

We want user interactions to be as safe as possible on Skout. Read about our commitment to online safety at http://www.skout.com/onlineSafetyTips.jsp. If you are a member of our teen community, Skout encourages you to discuss with your parent(s) or guardian(s) online safety issues for all of your social media memberships, including your Skout account.

## Disclosure to Protect Abuse Victims 

Notwithstanding any other provision of this Policy, Skout reserves the right, but has no obligation, to disclose any Information that you submit to Skout, if in its sole opinion, Skout suspects or has reason to suspect, that the Information involves a party who may be the victim of abuse in any form. Abuse may include, without limitation, elder abuse, child abuse, spousal abuse, neglect, or domestic violence. Information may be disclosed to authorities that Skout, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate to handle such disclosure. Appropriate authorities may include, without limitation, law enforcement agencies, child protection agencies, or court officials. 

## Questions?

Please [contact us](mailto:support@skout.com) if you have any questions about this Policy.
